Go out,
就是前面
turn left for 500 meters,
出了门左转五百米
and I'll pass a small shop.
然后路过一个小卖部
Is that the place
就能到
you're talking about?
你说的那个地方了
Yes, sir.
是的先生
Any good places
那还没有什么
to eat around there?
好吃的地方
I'll send the info to your phone.
我回头一并发您手机上
Great, thanks.
好 好 好
[Reach out if you need anything.]
有事联系我啊
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
I thought you'd leave
我以为我刚来
right after I arrived.
你们就要走了呢
Xiaoning still has
因为小涂
some things to finish,
还有一些事没有办完
so I
所以我呢
can't leave yet.
也一时半会走不了
Your trainee is persistent.
你这个徒弟够有韧劲的
Yuhui will sign tomorrow,
小唐明儿就要签约了
but Xiaoning is still trying?
她还不服输啊
You used
以前跟我们
to say
套近乎的时候
Xiaoning
一口一个
all the time,
小涂 小涂
now
现在呢
it's
一口一个
Yuhui.
小唐 小唐
Change of heart?
叛变了
No way.
哪儿能呢
But business
但干业务吗
is tough
就是这么残酷
and survival of the fittest.
适者生存
Xiaoning will
小涂早晚
learn this soon.
都会上这一课的
After all,
毕竟
not everyone is...
不是所有人都跟我一样
Thick-skinned.
厚脸皮
I...
在这
Right.
是
Why are you
你这么急匆匆地
in such a rush?
去哪儿啊
Why do you care?
我上哪儿去关你屁事
Can't I go out
我不能出去溜达溜达
and have some fun?
找点乐子
If you have money, pay me back.
你有钱倒是还我一点啊
How about
那这样吧
taking me along,
带我一起去
going toward the interest?
抵扣利息
I'm free now anyway.
反正我现在也没事
You're free?
你没事啊
Go pick up shells on the beach.
没事去海边捡贝壳
Where I'm going
姐去的地方
isn't for you.
不适合你
But
那还有什么地方
where's that?
不适合我
Hello.
你好
[Hello.]
您好
Leave this bag at the front desk.
麻烦帮我把这包搁前台
I'll pick it up later.
我回来拿
Sure, no problem.
好的 好的
Thanks.
谢谢啊
Turn left for 500 meters, right?
左转五百米对不对
[Yes.]
对
Geez.
吓我一跳
Flicking your hair like that.
甩个头发甩那么大动静
What's there to do here for fun?
这地方有什么乐子呀
Whose dog left a mess?
谁家的狗狗乱拉粑粑
Is she aware
她是不是知道
I'm following her?
我跟着她呀
Is she leading me
故意带着我在这儿
in circles on purpose?
绕来绕去的
Why do I feel like
这地方绕来绕去的
I'm going
怎么总感觉是
in circles?
原地打转啊
No one around,
一个人也没有
and no phone signal.
连手机信号也没有
Rao Jing!
饶静
It's Zhao Fanggang!
我是赵方刚
Hello,
你好
anyone home?
有人吗
I'm lost.
我 我迷路了
Can someone
我想问一下
help me get out?
就是怎么才能走出去
Anyone?
我 我想问一下路
Excuse me,
不好意思啊
I got lost.
我迷路了
Can you point me the way out?
想问问怎么才能走出去
Sorry,
真不好意思
I...
我
I'm just asking for directions.
我是想问路的
I wandered
我迷路了
in here by mistake.
不小心闯进来了
Sorry.
真对不起
Please don't blame me.
莫怪 莫怪
I'll leave now.
我这就走
Did you enjoy scaring me?
吓我好玩吗
Was that funny?
好玩吗
Why are you here?
你来这儿干什么
Aren't you afraid of getting lost?
七拐八拐的也不怕迷路
You're pretty brave.
胆子也真够大的
Mr. Zhao,
不是赵经理
are you crazy?
你有毛病吧你
You followed me here.
是你跟踪我到这儿的
I...
我
I came here
我是看这个宣
because of
宣传册来
this brochure.
来这儿的
Brochure guide?
宣传册导游图
Does it have my house on it?
上面有我家吗
Your house?
你家
Playing with me again.
又玩我
It says Rao Yong,
这叫饶勇
and you're Rao...
你叫饶
Jing.
静
Yes,
对啊
Rao Yong is my dad,
饶勇我爸
and that's my mom.
那个是我妈
Since you're here,
那来都来了
let me introduce you.
我给你介绍一下吧
Dad, Mom,
爸妈
this is
这位呢
my colleague
是我的同事
and debtor,
兼债主
Zhao Fanggang.
赵方刚同志
[He]
他呢
[reminds me to repay my debt]
每天准时的早 午 晚
[every morning, noon, and night,]
提醒我要还债
so
所以呢
please
我希望
remember
你们能好好记住
his face
他的样子
and bless him.
并且好好保佑他
Oh, actually,
叔叔 阿姨
there is
这点小事
no need
就不 不麻烦你们了
to trouble you.
也不用你们操心
We
我跟
are
饶经理
good colleagues
是好同事
and friends.
好朋友
In that case,
那关系这么好
then give 3 bows.
磕三个吧
Get up now.
起来吧
Don't rush,
别着急
take it slow.
慢一点
Not bad.
可以啊
I've been fishing for so long,
我钓了这么久
and with your help,
才在你的帮助下
I only caught this small fish.
钓了一条这么小的鱼
Mr. Yang
那杨总
is an expert angler.
是个钓鱼高手
How can I attract him?
能吸引得了他吗
Therefore,
所以啊
casting a wide net
广撒网
isn't as good as mastering a skill.
其实不如一门专的
You mean
你的意思是
learning a unique skill?
学一门绝技
I saw a lot of
我刚刚看这附近
yellowfish nearby.
有很多黄鱼
I can teach you the no-bait fishing.
我可以教给你空钩钓法
It might
说不定
attract Mr. Yang.
能吸引到杨总
No-bait fishing?
空钩钓法
Without bait?
不用鱼饵啊
Yes,
不用
but it's difficult.
不过这个确实很难
It requires precise angle and force,
对抛竿的角度和力度
and the rod's hardness and length
以及鱼竿的硬度和长度
are crucial.
都有极高的要求
If you mentioned it,
你既然说了
there must be
就肯定有什么
a quick way.
速成的办法
The key
其实最重要的一点
is the hook.
就是那个朝天钩
If the hook is right,
钩子下对了
you're halfway there.
你就成功一半了
I know a place nearby
我知道这旁边有一个
that specializes in fishing gear.
专门做渔具的地方
No,
不行
for
这种东西
perfect accuracy,
想要百发百中
we have to make it ourselves.
必须得咱们自己做
I saw
我刚刚看那边
some materials over there.
有很多材料
I can give it a try.
我可以试一下
You can make this?
你还会做这个
You really know everything.
你也太全能了吧
There's a lot you don't know about me.
不知道的还有很多呢
The fishing community is small.
其实这个垂钓圈子很小
Since Mr. Yang
既然杨总
loves fishing,
那么痴迷于钓鱼
if someone tells him
如果有人告诉他
there's a challenger
这小岛上
on the island,
来了一个挑战者的话
he'll be thrilled.
他一定会很惊喜
Be confident.
要自信一点
You need confidence
你只有大胆自信了
to succeed.
才能够成功
Miss,
小姑娘
fishing with no bait at your age,
年纪轻轻的空钩钓鱼
impressive!
不得了啊
Only 3 people
这岛上
on this island
能空钩钓鱼的
can do this.
不出三个
All with years of experience.
都是有多年经验的
Your master
你师父
must be
肯定是个
a fishing expert.
垂钓高手吧
Yes,
我师父啊
he's indeed great.
他确实挺厉害的
I will
等有机会
introduce you
我介绍我师父
to him sometime.
跟二位认识一下
Are you
小姑娘
coming back tomorrow?
你明天还来不来
[Our fishing community]
我们这个垂钓圈子
[has been studying]
最近一直在研究这
[this method.]
空钩钓法
[I'd like to invite everyone]
我想把大家都叫上来
[to watch.]
观摩 观摩
Depends on the weather.
那要看天气了
I checked the forecast.
我今天看天气预报
It might rain tomorrow.
明天好像有雨的
The weather here
我们小岛这天气啊
changes
就像孩子的脸
quickly.
说变就变
Be sure
说好了
to come if you can.
一定要来啊
Sure.
行
I'll
那
come tomorrow.
我明天来
Good.
明天见啊
Sure.
好嘞
See you.
明天见
Bye.
再见
Is she nuts?
她有病吧
Her parents have passed away.
双亲都去世了
She's all alone
她一个人在这个世界上
in the world.
孑然一身
Poor thing.
也怪可怜的
Sir, ma'am,
叔叔 阿姨
I really wandered in there
我白天真是
by mistake during the day.
不小心才闯进来的
Please forgive me.
大人不记小人过
I'll bow
我在这儿
3 more times.
再给你们磕三个头了
Good night.
晚安
Hello?
喂
Come to the window.
你到窗边来
I'm about to leave,
我要出发了
just letting you know.
跟你说一声
Xiaoning,
筱柠姐
morning.
早
Xiaoning,
小涂
what's got you so happy
你大清早地看什么呢
this early?
这么高兴
Just out here enjoying the sea.
我出来看看海
[What about you?]
你们呢
Where are you heading for?
你们干吗去啊
[We're off to sign a contract.]
我们去签一下合同
Dressed like that,
筱柠姐你穿成这样
are you going fishing?
是去钓鱼吗
Yeah,
对
since the contract didn't go through,
反正合同没签成
[I might as well]
那也不能白来啊
[enjoy the trip.]
就当旅游了
Have fun then.
那玩开心
Stay safe.
注意安全啊
Sure.
好
Thanks.
谢谢
Let's go.
走吧
I'm off.
我走了
Stay safe.
注意安全啊
Bye.
拜拜
Hey, you're here.
小姑娘来了
Hello.
你好
Mr. Yang,
杨总
the girl who knows
昨天我给你说那个
[no-bait fishing]
会空钩钓法的小姑娘
[is here.]
来了
[Hi Mr. Yang,]
杨总您好
I'm Tu Xiaoning from Dairui.
我是代瑞的涂筱柠
Nice to meet you.
见到你很高兴
You're
你就是
Tu Xiaoning?
涂筱柠
You know each other?
你们认识
That's great.
那太好了
Kindred spirits are hard to come by.
难得遇到知音
I'm gonna leave you alone.
那 你们切磋切磋
Have fun.
我去忙一会儿
Thanks.
好
Not many young
很少有年轻人
know no-bait fishing.
会空钩钓法
It takes years of practice.
这需要很多年经验
Experience helps,
经验是一回事
but it's all about the right approach.
主要是要对症下药
No-bait fishing
空钩钓法
is for yellowfish.
主要针对的是黄鱼
They have OCD,
它们有严重的强迫症
so anything in their nest
只要窝里有东西
has to go.
就一定要叼出去
Live bait
用活饵
can scare them,
反而会刺激到它们
so using a bare hook
不如用空钩
is better.
对症下药
Our custom hook
我们制定的朝天钩
is sensitive
灵敏度极高
and accurate.
百发百中
Impressive.
不错
The right approach is key.
对症下药很重要
Just like knowing what clients like
正如你懂得投其所好
and meeting their needs.
把握客户
Mr. Yang, you found out.
杨总您知道了
All client managers
每一个客户经理
will try their best
都会竭尽全力地
to win over their clients.
争取自己的客户
I'm just
我只是
hoping for
想争取一个
a chance to meet you.
见杨总您的机会
Then,
我见了您
you'll know
您才会知道
if my plan for your company
我给您企业制定的方案
suits your needs.
是不是投其所好
Alright,
好
let's hear
那我就
your plan
听一听你的方案
and see if
看看你是不是
you came prepared.
有备而来
Thanks.
好
So, did he show up?
怎么样来没来
I couldn't get in touch with him.
没联系上
When I asked him last night,
我昨晚约他的时候
he said he might not
他就说今天
have time today.
不一定有时间
Why didn't you mention that earlier?
不是你怎么不早说呀
Yuhui,
小唐
don't worry.
你先别着急
Please try reaching out to him again.
那辛苦你再联系一下吧
Okay.
好
Hurry up!
你快点
Patience.
别急
Your interest rate
你给的利率
is higher than other banks.
比其他银行的都高
Why do you think
凭什么觉得
I'd pick your plan?
我会青睐你的方案
While the rate is a bit higher,
虽然利率是高一些
the loan term is longer
但融资方案
and the amount is larger, so the
贷款周期长额度大
short-term repayment pressure is less.
短期还款压力小
This might fit better
可能更符合
with your long-term business plan.
您对企业的长期规划
Really?
是吗
I visited your factory
我去过您的厂房
and got to know your strategy.
了解了您的发展战略
Over the next 3 to 5 years,
未来三到五年
you're bound to expand and capture
杨总您一定开疆拓土
the golden period of market growth.
抢占市场的黄金发展期
You'll need
这样的话就更需要一笔
steady cash flow for that.
流动资金做保障了
My plan
我的这个方案呢
fits perfectly,
恰好
with a
契合了这一点
3-year term.
周期是三年
After that,
三年以后
the loan can automatically renew
可自动融资
without principal repayment.
也就是无还本续贷
You won't have the stress
您不需要承担筹钱
of raising funds,
还款 再贷的这个压力
repaying, and reapplying for a loan,
更不需要担心
and you'll have continuous capital flow.
资金会无法连续下去
Other banks'
表面上看
annual loan
其他银行
interest rates
一年的贷款利率
might seem lower,
确实是合算一点
but the actual
但实际上呢
yearly repayment pressure
您每年还款的时候
and hidden interest rates
压力有多大
are high.
隐形的利率有多高
As a boss,
您作为老板
you know this.
心里一定是有本账的吧
They told me yesterday
昨天他们跟我说啊
that a young fishing expert
说海边来了一个
was at the seaside.
年轻的垂钓大神
I had a hunch it was you.
我就隐约猜到了
I'm sorry, Mr. Yang.
对不起啊杨总
I really
我确实
needed a chance
非常需要一个机会
to meet you.
可以跟您见一面
Honestly,
说真的啊
most young
你们这个年纪的
people today
姑娘小伙
grew up in comfort.
都是在蜜罐里长大的
They're impatient
浮躁
and can't endure hardships.
吃不了苦的我见多了
But your persistence and determination
像你这么执着还较劲的
are rare.
倒是少见
I'm not sure
说实话啊
about your
你这个钓鱼的水平
fishing skills,
我不知道怎么样
but
但是
you've made
你这个钩子
a very good hook.
做得不错
Jing.
静姐
Xiaoning,
小涂
how's it going?
现在怎么样了
Is Mr. Yang interested
杨总对你的方案
in your proposal?
感兴趣了
Pretty much.
十有七八吧
I've done all I can.
反正我已经尽人事了
Now it's up to fate.
剩下的就听天命
Well done.
做得好
[So, Mr. Yang]
原来杨总今天
[was with you today.]
是跟你在一起啊
Fanggang.
小赵哥
Xiaoning,
小涂
impressive!
厉害啊
You've learned to divert attention.
现在都懂调虎离山了
Tang Yuhui and I
我跟唐羽卉
waited in Mr. Yang's
在杨总的办公室
office all day,
生生坐了大半天
our butts got sore,
那屁股都给我坐疼了
and all we got was a call
最后等来一通电话
saying the deal's off.
不签了
Where's Tang Yuhui?
唐羽卉呢
She disappeared.
不见了
What do you mean?
什么叫不见了
You didn't even look for her?
不见了你也不找找
Weren't you
不是之前还
close just now?
小唐 小唐的吗
Why should I look for her?
我找她干吗
I came all this way,
我千里迢迢过来
didn't make any money,
钱没赚着
just ended up waiting around.
净跟这儿等人了
Xiaoning,
小涂
don't forget about me
你可不能见利忘我啊
if Mr. Yang becomes
杨总要是成为了你的
your first loan client.
第一个贷款客户
You'll have to treat me to a meal.
得请吃饭
Mr. Zhao,
赵经理
as Xiaoning's senior,
作为小涂的前辈
if she successfully signs the deal,
如果她签单成功了
shouldn't you be
是不是也应该
treating her to a meal?
你请她吃饭呢
Sure,
请啊
she can treat me first,
她请完我
then I'll treat her.
我再请她吗
Jing,
静姐
Fanggang,
小赵哥
it's a long day for me.
我累了一天了
I'm tired.
风吹日晒的
I want to go back,
我想回去
take a shower, and sleep.
赶紧洗个澡睡觉
You two go ahead and eat.
你们俩去吃吧
I'm heading back.
我先走了
Okay.
好
Have a good sleep.
那美美地睡上一觉吧
Bye.
拜拜
Let's go.
走吧
Join me
咱俩
for some food.
吃饭去
That was exciting.
真刺激啊
They went
小赵哥跟静姐他们
to eat.
去吃饭了
No one will see us.
不会有人看到我们的
Why didn't you
那你怎么
go with them?
没跟着一起去啊
Someone was waiting for me.
这不是有人等着我呢吗
Xiaoning,
小涂同志
done with work
忙完工作
and finally remembered me?
终于想起我来了
Even when I'm super busy,
我百忙之中
I always remember Mr. Ji.
心里一直记着纪老师
I told you,
都说了
after work,
下班时间
don't call me Mr. Ji.
不要叫我纪老师
Hungry?
饿了
I haven't eaten all day.
我一天没吃饭了
Let's
好
get something to eat.
带你吃好吃的去
Go.
走
Ma'am,
老板
we'll have a...
要一
A seafood platter!
要一个海鲜大拼盘
One seafood platter.
海鲜大拼盘一个
Spicy snails!
爆炒钉螺
[Grouper fish!]
石斑鱼
Garlic vermicelli scallops!
蒜蓉粉丝扇贝
Vermicelli scallops!
粉丝扇贝
I apologize for that.
不好意思啊
I tend to
老板我这人平时说话
speak quite loudly.
嗓门比较大
[That should be all.]
就这些吧
Let me see how much it hurts you.
我帮你算一下多少钱啊
No need for that.
不用了
It's 396 yuan.
一共三百九十六
Here.
来
Keep the change.
不用找了
OK, thank you.
好 谢谢
Is there anything else
你要看看
you'd like to eat?
还想吃点什么吗
You locals are the experts
这个西海镇的美食
on the delicacies here.
还是你们本地人最懂
I heard you
我刚才听见你
ordered quite a bit.
点了很多啊
Yesterday I ordered two dishes,
昨天我点两个菜
and you almost made me return one.
你恨不得都让我退一个
Why feeling generous
今天怎么了
all of a sudden?
突然大方起来
Yesterday we split the bill.
昨天是平摊钱
Today you're buying.
今天是你买单
I'm buying?
我买单
When did I say I'd buy?
我什么时候说我买单了
We're on your turf.
你是东道主啊
You should do it.
那自然是你买单
What's the logic?
我是东道主我就要买单
As a local, treating guests
作为东道主请客呢
is a courtesy.
是情分
Not treating is the norm.
不请客是本分
We don't have that kind of courtesy.
咱们俩没情分
I won't do it.
不请
No matter how expensive
你平时花钱如流水
the bag and wine are,
买大几万的包
you've never hesitated
喝大几千的酒
to spend money on that.
眼睛都不眨一下
Can't you be a bit more generous?
你就不能大方一点
Treat a good colleague
照顾一下
who takes care of you all the time?
平时照顾你的同事吗
How I spend my money
我平时挣钱怎么花
is none of your business.
跟你有什么关系
Besides,
再说了
when have you ever taken care of me?
你什么时候照顾过我
Aren't I taking care of you right now?
我这不就在照顾你吗
If I didn't see you all alone,
要不是看你一个人
lonely and helpless,
孤苦伶仃
I wouldn't be having dinner with you.
我才不陪你吃饭呢
I'm lonely and helpless?
我孤苦伶仃
For your information.
我告诉你
I make money and spend it on myself.
我一个人挣钱一个人花
I don't have mouths to feed.
一人吃饱全家不饿
I meet countless clients every day,
我每天见不完的客户
and have endless booty calls.
约不完的弟弟
I'm living my life freely.
我潇洒着呢我
Sure.
是
You're the most carefree.
你最潇洒
Then who was that again?
那是谁
Passed out drunk in a bar at midnight,
大半夜醉倒在酒吧
crying and refusing to go home.
哭着喊着不回家
Guess that's 'cause no one was home.
敢情是家里没人呗
You know me well.
你也知道我这个人
I don't hold back my words.
嘴上没个把门的
I was talking nonsense.
胡说八道 你
Don't take it to heart.
你别往心里去
Rao Jing.
饶静
Please
老板
pack it up for me, I'll get it later.
帮我打包我回来取
This place is usually
这个地方一般都是
for locals.
本地人来
I don't think we'll run into
我觉得肯定不会
Ms. Rao and the others.
遇到静姐他们
Alright, don't be upset.
好了别生气了
That was my fault.
刚才是我不对
I apologize.
我跟你道歉
I'm sorry.
对不起
Alright.
你这样
I'm buying dinner.
我请你吃饭
What would you like?
你想吃什么
Order whatever you like.
随便点
For your information,
但我跟你说啊
you've only got one chance
放我血的机会
to bleed me dry.
只有这么一次
Don't miss it.
机不可失
You won't get another shot.
时不再来
I want the most
那我要吃那个
expensive yellow croaker.
最贵的黄花鱼
You're ferocious.
这么狠
Alright.
得
What's wrong?
怎么了
Don't you like it here?
你不喜欢这儿
What's going on?
怎么了 怎么了
I think I just saw Rao Jing.
好像是饶静
Hold on.
你等会儿
Why are Fanggang
小赵哥他们
and Jing here?
怎么在这儿啊
Let's bail.
快跑
I think I just saw
我刚才好像看到
Xiaoning with a guy.
小涂跟一个男的
That guy
那男的
seems to be the boss.
好像是咱领导
We haven't started drinking yet.
还没喝就晕了
I was planning to treat you
本来想请你
to a big island feast.
吃一顿海岛大餐的
An authentic one.
地道的
Finally,
没想到
we have to do it ourselves.
还要我们自己动手
Freshly caught.
自己动手新鲜打捞
We'll start a fire later.
一会儿再生一团火
This is the real island snack.
这才是地道的海岛小吃
Aren't you the one
你是不是就是
that people talk about online,
网上说的那种
a partner who stabilizes emotions
有稳定情绪的伴侣呀
and provides emotional support
随时随地地
anytime and anywhere.
提供情绪价值
I remember back in school.
我怎么记得上学那会儿
You're always
你也总是
the one comforting others.
安慰别人的那个
Back then,
上学那会儿
we weren't even close.
我们熟吗
It seems we hardly spoke.
好像没说上几句话呀
You know,
上学那会儿
you're quite loud.
你嗓门比较大
Every time I passed by,
每次我经过的时候
I could hear you.
都能听到
And
而且那时候
you didn't seem to
你好像也没有什么
have any worries.
烦心事
None at all.
没有
At that time,
那会儿
I was cheerful every day.
每天乐呵呵地
The only worry I had was
唯一的烦心事就是
thinking about how to
每天想着怎么跟我妈
outsmart my mom
斗智斗勇的
to get some pocket money.
要零花钱
Full of passion and positivity,
一腔的热血正能量
I used to provide warmth to others.
都替别人发光发热
Always warming others.
老替别人发光发热
So why did you always
那为什么之前
feel no one liked you before?
总觉得没有人喜欢你
Oh,
也是
good question.
你这么说
There should be someone like that.
也许还真有人喜欢我
I just didn't realize it.
只是我不知道
After all, I was kind of
那个时候怎么说也是
kind and cute,
又善良又可爱
which could be considered shining.
也算闪闪发光了
It's just that
只不过
compared to someone like you,
跟你这种一站在人群中
who stands out in a crowd,
就很耀眼的人
it's different.
比起来不一样
My little virtues
我这点优良品德
might
可能
need someone to discover them
需要有人发现
and explore them
然后深挖
to bring them out.
才能挖出来
So it seems I'm quite lucky.
那看起来我很幸运啊
I've discovered a treasure.
深挖到了一个宝贝
What do you like about me?
你喜欢我什么呀
Do I need a reason?
一定要有一个理由吗
Of course.
当然了
Just like a shell,
就像是贝壳一样
when you discover it
你发现了它
and find it beautiful,
觉得它很漂亮
then you're willing to
你才愿意
dig it out with all your might
使劲把它挖出来
and take it home.
然后带回家
Smart.
聪明
Hardworking.
努力
Ambitious.
上进
These are all your strengths.
这些都是你的优点
But they're not why I fall for you.
但不是我喜欢你的理由
I wouldn't fall for
我也不会喜欢上
others who have these strengths either.
其他具有这些优点的人
I have no reason
我喜欢你
to like you.
只是因为你是你
But...
可是
That's all.
没有可是
Actually, you mean
其实你对我
more to me
比你想象当中要
than you think.
更为重要一些
No need to overanalyze.
你不要说得这么深刻
You're making
显得我
my feelings for you shallow.
对你的喜欢很肤浅
Then tell me,
那说来听听
how shallow is it?
有多肤浅
I just think you're good-looking.
我就是觉得你长得好看
Didn't hear you.
没听见
Say it louder.
大声一点
I just think you're good-looking.
我就觉得你好看
You fit my aesthetic.
长在了我的审美点上
I've heard that before.
这点我之前就听说过了
Who told you?
你听谁说的
When did you find out?
你什么时候知道的呀
It's a secret.
秘密
Who told you?
谁说的
Who told you exactly?
谁跟你说的呀
Say it.
你跟我说一下吗
It's almost done.
马上就快好了啊
I want spicy ones.
我要吃辣的
Spicy, spicy!
辣的 辣的
OK.
好
It's your phone.
你电话响了
It's mom.
妈的电话
Hello, mom.
喂 妈
Mom,
妈
how you doing?
身体怎么样
[Xiaoning.]
筱柠啊
I'm doing well.
好着呢 好着呢
Your dad and mom
你爸爸妈妈呀
cook for me every day.
天天给我做好吃的
[Just now,]
刚才
[they forced me]
又逼着我
[to have two bowls of pigeon soup.]
喝了两碗鸽子汤呢
[Talk to your mom.]
你跟妈妈说
[Xiaoning.]
筱柠
[Mom.]
妈
[What's wrong with you?]
你怎么回事啊
Other people's kids go on business trips,
人家别人的孩子出差
and their parents call them
一天恨不得
hundreds of times a day.
打八百个电话
Look at you,
你看看你
not even calling me once.
一个电话都不给我打
Even if I call you that many times,
我给你打八百个电话
aren't you supposed to
工作不是还得
finish your own work?
你自己做吗
Your safety comes first.
这平安就好
Besides,
再说了
hasn't Yuheng been by your side?
小纪不是在你身边的吗
[Cherish your time together.]
珍惜你们的二人世界
[Right.]
对呀
[Make sure to go back early.]
早点回去
[Get some rest.]
早点休息啊
[Don't worry.]
放心吧
[I'm doing well.]
好着呢啊
[See ya.]
拜拜
OK.
行
Take it easy, mom.
放心吧妈
Have some more.
多吃点
[This place is gorgeous.]
这个地方真美
Do you come back often?
你总回来吗
My first visit since my parents died.
爸妈走以后第一次回来
So you have
那你这边
no family left in here now?
一个亲人都没有了
It's too quiet here.
西海镇太安静了
By eight or nine in the evening,
到了晚上八九点的时候
there aren't many on the street.
街上就没什么人了
It's empty.
空空荡荡的
My name implies quietness,
虽然我的名字叫饶静
but I prefer liveliness.
但是我更喜欢热闹
Staying here makes me feel uneasy.
在西海镇待着静得发慌
I'm more comfortable
还是在
living in a big city.
大城市待得自在
It's not that you prefer liveliness.
那你不是喜欢热闹
You're simply afraid of being alone.
你是害怕孤单
Maybe.
也许吧
So sometimes,
所以有时候
I'm kind of jealous of you.
我挺羡慕你的
Your life is real and lively.
你的生活真实 热闹
You are very petty at work.
工作当中呢全是小心眼
But still
但是一点都不耽误
you're quite naive in life.
你在生活当中缺心眼
You don't hide
一点心眼都没有
your true self at all.
想占便宜就占便宜
You won't feel embarrassed.
也不会不好意思
That's pretty good.
挺好的
So are you complimenting me
那你这是夸我
or insulting me?
还是损我呀
Insulting.
损
OK.
行
I'm just an ordinary guy.
我吧就是一俗人
Just a commoner.
老百姓吗
Living a simple
平平淡淡
and ordinary life.
普普通通地活着
Enduring bad tempers for low pay.
为点散碎银两看人脸色
Calculating for some vested interests.
为点既得利益算计着
Worrying about daily necessities.
为柴米油盐操心着
For my parents, my wife and kids...
为父母 为妻女
I don't have a wife yet.
我还没有媳妇啊
In short,
总之
I carry the burden for my family.
为家人扛着吧
For family...
为家人扛着
You know what?
你知道吗
Since my parents passed away,
自从我父母走以后
I've told myself
我就告诉自己
to live without burdens.
无负无累
Don't create trouble for myself
别给自己找麻烦
or try to build any relationships.
去建立什么人际关系
If everything could
如果一切都能
be easily let go,
轻易放下的话
then there wouldn't be any burdens.
就不会有什么负担
But sometimes I find myself thinking,
可是有时候我又在想
if in my life,
如果我生活当中
everyone and everything
所有的人跟事
loses their significance,
都失去了重量
then what
那我的生活
is the meaning of my life?
还有什么意义
You seem to be referring
你这个好像是
to a theory
有一个
called...
说法叫什么理论
The backpack theory.
背包理论
The emptier the backpack,
背包越空
the easier a person feels.
人就越轻松
You know,
你啊
you're living in paradox.
就是活得太拧巴了
You're afraid of loneliness,
又害怕孤独
yet you feel life is meaningless.
又觉得生活没意义
What do you know?
你懂什么呀
Women are inherently complicated.
女人本来就拧巴
OK.
行
Then let's embrace
那咱们今天
the complexity today.
也拧巴一下吧
Get rid of all worries!
不要不快乐
Be happy!
要开心
You know,
你知道吗
when I'm
我
unhappy,
不开心的时候
or happy.
开心的时候
I like to
我都喜欢
dance.
跳舞
I want to
我 要放一首
play my favorite song.
我最喜欢的曲子
I need to head back now.
我要回去了
Otherwise,
要不然
Jing will definitely suspect me.
静姐肯定会怀疑的
You understand, right?
理解的
Sure.
当然
You won't be upset, right?
不会生气吧
Not at all.
不生气
It's getting really late.
今天也太晚了
Just head back and take a hot shower.
早点回去洗个热水澡
Then get some sleep.
睡觉吧
I'm going back then.
那我走了
Go ahead.
去吧
Ji Yuheng!
纪昱恒
What's up?
怎么了
Mr. Yang just sent me a message.
杨总刚才给我发消息
He said we can meet tomorrow.
说明天我们可以见一面
Then
然后
he'll apply for a loan.
就申请贷款
Really?
真的
I didn't expect him
我也没有想到
to agree.
他会同意
Congratulations!
恭喜啊
Xiaoning.
筱柠
You're awesome.
真棒
But I think
不过我倒觉得
it's only natural.
是情理之中的事情
You're so talented.
你这么优秀
He would definitely choose you.
他肯定会选择你
Really?
真的吗
Of course.
当然
There's camera.
有监控
What?
监控
Where?
在哪里
I kind of regret
有点后悔
letting you go back.
让你回去了
I don't want to leave either.
我也不想走啊
Just head back.
快回吧
I'm going.
我走了啊
Ms. Rao,
饶经理
this apprentice of yours
您这个 徒弟
is quite impressive.
了不得
Mr. Yang.
杨总
Rest assured.
您放心吧
Xiaoning will
小涂肯定不会
not let you down.
让您失望的
Jing,
静姐
where's Fanggang?
小赵哥呢
Let me buy you lunch.
我请你们俩吃个饭吧
He
他
might still be sleeping off
可能昨天晚上喝多了
last night's drinks.
还没醒吧
Why bring him along?
再说了带他干吗
Haven't you been
你这两天
eating with him these past days?
不总跟他一起吃饭吗
You've got it wrong.
你看错了
Mr. Zhao,
赵先生
here's your hangover remedy.
您的醒酒药
Thank you.
谢谢
Yeah.
对
About that new
那个新增
[deposit confirmation,]
存款的确认书
[I've already]
我已经
emailed to you.
给你发到邮箱里了
Right.
对
Ji Yuheng?
领导
Is too much beer causing
是 是我喝多了吗
eye strain?
眼花
Fanggang, are you OK?
小赵哥你没事吧
Are you still hangover?
酒还没醒啊
I think I just saw the boss
我刚才好像看见领导
go into that room.
进了那个屋
You must be mistaken.
你看错了
[You should go take a shower and sober up.]
你回去洗个澡醒醒酒吧
[Look,]
你看
you could barely stand straight.
你站都站不稳了
This isn't good.
你这样不行
You're seeing things.
都出现幻觉了
You should cut down on alcohol.
以后少喝点酒吧
C'mon, I can stand straight!
谁说我站不稳了
I do feel a bit unsteady.
我确实有点站不稳了
I need to lie down.
我得回去躺着
But didn't you plan to buy a ticket
那不是说今天要走吗
this afternoon and leave?
买下午的票
You're not leaving?
不走了
Forget it!
走什么走 走什么走
I can barely walk!
我连走路都走不动道了
I'll leave with you two
我明天下午
tomorrow afternoon.
跟你们一起走
Rao Jing,
饶静
you're the one who got me drunk.
是你把我灌醉的
You need to take responsibility.
你得对我负责任
What responsibility
我对你负什么责啊
do I have?
我负什么责任
You're an adult.
你这么大个人
Shame on you!
你要不要点脸
Stop acting crazy in here.
你在这走廊上发什么疯
You're a salesman, right?
你说你一个干营销的
And you let this little bit of beer
就这么一点啤酒
get you like this?
给你喝成这样
Get inside!
进去
You...
你
Good, good,
好 好 好
very good.
好得很
Useless.
废物
I...
我
[Did you sleep?]
睡了吗
[Not yet.]
没有啊
[You almost got caught by]
今天又差点
[Fanggang today.]
被小赵哥发现
[I couldn't just go to see you.]
我也不敢去找你
[What are you doing?]
你在干什么呢
[Without you by my side,]
没有你在
[I can only bury myself in work.]
只好用工作麻痹自己了
Jing.
静姐
Why come to me
怎么突然想着
all of a sudden?
回来找我啊
I miss you.
想你了呀
Get some good sleep.
今天好好睡
I'll help you sleep.
哄你睡觉
Aren't you the one
你是不是就是
that people talk about online,
网上说的那种
a partner who stabilizes emotions
有稳定情绪的伴侣呀
and provides emotional support
随时随地地
anytime and anywhere.
提供情绪价值
I remember back in school.
我怎么记得上学那会儿
You're always
你也总是
the one comforting others.
安慰别人的那个
Back then,
上学那会儿
we weren't even close.
我们熟吗
It seems we hardly spoke.
好像没说上几句话啊
You know,
上学那会儿
you were quite loud.
你嗓门比较大
Every time I passed by,
每次我经过的时候
I could hear you.
都能听到
And
而且那时候
you didn't seem
你好像
to have any worries.
也没有什么烦心事
Stop crying.
你别哭了
You only dropped two places, right?
你不 才掉两名吗
You're still in the top ten.
你还是前十名啊
Look at me, I'm always at the bottom.
你看我一直在尾巴
Why are you crying?
你哭什么
Stop.
别哭了
Your mom doesn't like it when you cry.
阿姨不喜欢你哭
If you went home with puffy eyes,
你红着眼睛回去
she would be upset.
阿姨会生气的
I have a good idea.
你这样吧
Just tell her
你就
that even
跟阿姨说
after dropping two places,
你说我才掉了两名
you're still in the top ten,
我还是前十名
but I've always been
你看涂筱柠
at the bottom.
永远在尾巴
She's lucky to have
你幸亏摊上
someone like you.
我这么个姑娘
If she had someone
你要摊上
like me as her daughter,
涂筱柠那样的姑娘
she'd be in deep trouble.
愁死了
Isn't that right?
是不是这么个道理
Have some water. Stop crying.
快喝点水 别哭了
[Smart.]
聪明
[Hardworking.]
努力
Ambitious.
上进
These are all your strengths.
这些都是你的优点
But they're not why I fall for you.
但不是我喜欢你的理由
I have no reason
我喜欢你
to like you.
只是因为你是你